Contact

jdholmes@tmhs.org

www.linkedin.com/in/jack-holmes-dnp-rn-ccrn-ne-c-402314bb (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Patient Safety Healthcare Nursing

Jack Holmes DNP, RN, CCRN, NE-C

Nurse Manager of CVICU, Debakey Heart and Vascular Center, Houston Methodist Hospital in The Texas Medical Center.

Houston, Texas Area

Summary

Experienced Nurse Leader in Acute Care, Critical Care, and Cath Lab. Total of 28 years of demonstrated work history with military and healthcare

industry. Strong educational background with a Doctor of Nursing Practice focused in Nursing Leadership from the University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston. Skilled in Nursing Leadership, Performance Improvement, Patient Safety, and Patient Satisfaction. Registered Nurse, Certified in Nursing Leadership and Critical Care Nursing.

Experience

Houston Methodist

Nurse Manager, 36 bed Cardiovascular Intensive Care Unit, Transplant and VADs

January 2018 - Present (2 years 5 months)

Houston, Texas

Houston Methodist

6 years

Nurse Manager, 30 bed Post Cardiac Surgical Unit 2014 - 2017 (3 years)

Houston, Texas Area

Nurse Manger-Cardiac Cath Lab 2011 - 2014 (3 years)

Baytown, Texas

Tenet Healthcare

Clinical Coordinator, Intensive Care Unit, Lakepointe Medical Center 2010 - 2012 (2 years)

Rowlett, Texas

Parkland Hospital

6 years

Associate Unit Manager-Cardiac Care Intensive Care Unit 2006 - 2009 (3 years)

Staff RN, Cardiac Telementry Unit, Cardiac Intensive Care Unit, Rapid Assessment Team Lead

2003 - 2006 (3 years)

Dallas, Texas

Olin E. Teague Veterans' Medical Center Phlebotomist, Nurse Technician, 12 week ICU Nurse internship 1999 - 2002 (3 years)

Temple, Texas

US Army US Army Active Duty enlisted 1991 - 1999 (8 years) 4 duty stations; Clinic Manager

Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

Doctor of Nursing, Nursing Leadership · (2015 - June 2017)

Texas Woman's University

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Execuitive (2008 - 2010)

University of Mary Hardin-Baylor

Bachelor's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2000 - 2002)